Works Progress Administration (WPA) Phonodisc Collection
Works Progress Administration (WPA) Phonodisc Collection
- 1941 season
  - Program No. 37 WPA American Folk Singers of Boston, 1941; wpa_phono_301; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Ezekiel Saw the Wheel, soloists, men's and women's choruses; [Where Should I Be] When the First Trumpet Sounds, soloists, men's and women's choruses; WPA spot: 5 years of WPA activities and benefits to society and defense; Hold Out Your Light, mixed chorus; There's Plenty Good Room in the Kingdom for Us All, mixed choruses.
  - Program No. 38 Northern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_302; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Symphony No. 41, Minuet in C Major "Jupiter"; Talk by Honorable Lewis Compton, Assistant Secretary of the Navy, on the U. S. Navy/WPA work; "Jupiter" Symphony: Finale.
  - Program No. 39 WPA American Folk Singers of Boston, 1941; wpa_phono_303; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    All songs performed a capella with soloists, men's & women's choruses. Every time I feel the Spirit; Good News; WPA spot - national defense work; Live Humble; I Want to Be Ready.
  - Program No. 40 Southern California WPA A. Capella Choir, 1941; wpa_phono_304; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Southern California WPA A Capella Choir performing. Kyrie from the First Mass, sung in Latin; Agnus Dei & Benedictus from the First Mass; Talk by Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. on the WPA/Defense, and Col. Francis C. Harrington, U.S. Army, recipient of Distinguished Service Award for his WPA work; Kyrie from Ave Maris Stella.
  - Program No. 41 WPA Negro Radio Unit of Southern California, 1941; wpa_phono_305; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    All sung a capella with soloists, men's, and women's choruses. Didn't my Lord deliver Daniel?; Keep me from sinking down; Who'll be a witness for my Lord?; WPA spot - WPA workers in the Defense Industries; Wade in the water; Every time I feel the spirit.
  - Program No. 42 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_306; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Introduction to Act II of Carmen; Talk by Sidney Toler (Charlie Chan) on the WPA advances in infrastructure, school lunches, literacy, and defense. Sidney gives a 'Chanism' at close; Finlandia
  - Program No. 43 Southern California WPA Negro Chorus, 1941; wpa_phono_307; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Amen Chorus, soloist, mixed chorus, a capella; Where shall I be? (When that first trumpet sounds), men's & women's choruses, piano accompaniment; Po' Mourner, soloist, mixed chorus, a capella; WPA spot - WPA Work Sign; You've gotta run, men's & women's choruses, soloist, piano accompaniment; Free Grace, men's & women's choruses, soloist, piano accompaniment.
  - Program No. 44 Southern California WPA Operatic Chorus with Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_308; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Polovetzian Dance from Prince Igor, part 1; Robert P. Patterson Undersecretary of War, on the WPA help in the national defense program; Polovetzian Dance from Prince Igor, part 2.
  - Program No. 45 Northern California WPA Negro Chorus, 1941; wpa_phono_309; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    All song performed a cappella. What kind of shoes you going to wear? (Golden slippers), soloist, mixed chorus; Let my people go, soloist, mixed chorus; To heaven I go, men's & women's choruses; WPA spot - 'America's Unemployed are on the march' Defense work; Deep River, soloists, mixed chorus; Have you got a good religion?, soloist, mixed chorus.
  - Program No. 46 Southern California WPA Negro Radio Unit, 1941; wpa_phono_310; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    All songs sung a capella. Gimme your hand, soloists, mixed chorus; Soon I will be done with the troubles of the world, mixed chorus; My God is so high, Arkansas origins, soloist, mixed choruses; WPA spot - "American's are Discovering America" American guide series; Feed my sheep, men's chorus, mixed chorus, soloist; Joshua fit the battle of Jericho, soloists, mixed chorus.
  - Program No. 47 Northern California Symphony Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_311; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Minuet from Symphony no. 1 in C major; WPA spot - first draftee and other WPA workers national defense; Finale from Beethoven's Symphony no. 1 in C major
  - Program No. 48 Southern California WPA Negro Chorus, 1941; wpa_phono_312; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Eagle builds her nest, soloist, mixed chorus, a capella; WPA National Defense spot with Morse code sound effect; Climbing up the mountain, men's, women's and mixed choruses, piano accompaniment; Steal away to Jesus, mixed chorus, soloist, a capella; I'm new born again, mixed chorus, soloist, piano accompaniment.
  - Program No. 49 Southern California Symphony Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_313; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Excerpts from Scott Bradley's Cartoonia, a four-movement orchestral suite of his music created for MGM's theatrical cartoons: Once Upon a Time; The Calico Dragon; Talk by Harriet Elliott on the WPA/OPA.; Fleas; The Brave Little Knight.
  - Program No. 50 New Jersey WPA Philharmonic Orchestra, 1941; wpa_phono_314; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    3rd movement from Symphony no. 5; Talk by Archibald MacLeish, poet and Librarian with Library of Congress, about the Library of Congress exhibition of work connected to national defense; Finale from Symphony no. 4.
  - Program No. 51 U. S. Army Band, 1941; wpa_phono_315; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Zacatecas March; American Fidelity March; Talk by General Henry H. Arnold, Deputy Chief of Staff U.S. Army, on Air Corps developments and WPA airfield construction; Babillage, Pageant of Progress March.
  - Program No. 52 Northern California WPA Negro Chorus, 1941; wpa_phono_316; folk songs and spirituals; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Swing Low, Sweet Chariot, soloists, mixed chorus, a capella; Sometimes I Feel Like a Motherless Child, soloist, men's, women's, and mixed choruses, a capella; WPA spot - health, educational, other advances; Deep River, soloists, mixed choruses, a capella.
- 1942 season
  - Program No. 1 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_317; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Calf of Gold, from Faust, sung by Robert Brink with men's chorus, orchestra; Hallelujah Chorus, from Christ on the Mount of Olives, oratorio, men's & women's choruses, orchestra; Talk by Jim & Marian Jordan (a.k.a. Fibber McGee & Molly), radio personalities, on schooling in the WPA, introduced by Harlow Wilcox; Soldier's Chorus, from Faust, men's & women's choruses, orchestra.
  - Program No. 2 New Jersey WPA Philharmonic Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_318; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    2nd movement in B minor, from Symphony no. 6; Talk by John M. Carmody, Administrator Federal Works Agency, on national defense - WPA outcomes and benefits; Prelude to Act 3, from Lohengrin.
  - Program No. 3 New Jersey WPA Philharmonic Orchestra; News Bulletin, 1941; wpa_phono_319; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Finale from Symphony no. 38 in D major; Late News Bulletin about the WPA & national defense, 2 announcers with telegraph sounder; Scherzo from Symphony no. 3.
  - Program No. 4 United States Army Band; Actual Recordings Air Raids of England, 1942; wpa_phono_320; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    All American March; Pageant of Progress; Recording of an actual air raid on England by Germany with description of events, Ralph Ingersoll, editor of NY Newspaper PM, on WPA defense work; Eyes Right March
  - Program No. 5 WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_321; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to Creatures of Prometheus; Talk by Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia, U. S. Director of Civilian Defense, on federal WPA and defense improvements; Scherzo from Midsummer Night's Dream.
  - Program No. 6 New York City WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_322; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    The Procession of the Sardar, from Caucasian Sketches Suite no. 1 Op. 10; Talk by Mischa Elman, violinist, on WPA muscicians, public morale, and music in national defense; Air for G String; Russian Sailor's Dance, from The Red Poppy ballet.
  - Program No. 7 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_323; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to La Clemenza di Tito; Talk by Walter Huston, actor, on WPA employment of film, radio, stage; Overture to Ruslan and Ludmilla.
  - Program No. 8 New Jersey WPA Philharmonic Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_324; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Interlude from Act IV of Carmen; Dance of the Sylphs from Damnation of Faust; Talk by Arthur Godfrey, radio personality, on the WPA workers; Hungarian March from Damnation of Faust.
  - Program No. 9 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 1], 1942; wpa_phono_325; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Praeludium; Scherzo in G Minor from Octet Op. 20; Talk by James C. Petrillo, president of the American Federation of Musicians, on the importance of music in national defense; Wedding March from Le coq d'or.
  - Program No. 9 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 2], 1942; wpa_phono_326; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 9 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 3], 1942; wpa_phono_327; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 9 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 4], 1942; wpa_phono_328; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 9 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 5], 1942; wpa_phono_329; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 10 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 1], 1942; wpa_phono_330; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to Abu Hassan; Talk by Lucy Monroe, singer, on patriotism and music; Monroe sings The Star Spangled Banner with organ accompaniment; Waltz from Eugene Onegin.
  - Program No. 10 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 2], 1942; wpa_phono_331; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 10 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 3], 1942; wpa_phono_332; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 10 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 4], 1942; wpa_phono_333; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
  - Program No. 10 Illinois WPA Symphony Orchestra [copy 5], 1942; wpa_phono_334; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to Abu Hassan; Talk by Lucy Monroe, singer, on patriotism and music; Monroe sings The Star Spangled Banner with organ accompaniment; Waltz from Eugene Onegin
  - Program No. 11 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_335; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    2nd movement from Symphony no. 8; Prelude to 3rd act of Lohengrin; Talk by Dr. William Fletcher Russell, Director of the National Citizenship Education Program; Negro chant
  - Program No. 12 New York City WPA Negro Melody Singers, 1942; wpa_phono_336; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    In Bright Mansions Above, soloist, men's, women's & mixed choruses, a capella; You Better Get Religion Sinner Man, men's, women's & mixed choruses, a capella; WPA spot - defense jobs in wartime, factory closings due to wartime priorities; Ride Up in the Chariot, men's, women's & mixed choruses, a capella; Old Black Joe, soloist John Garth, basso with piano accompaniment; Good News, Chariot's Coming, soloists, men's, women's & mixed choruses.
  - Program No. 13 New York City WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_337; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to The Marriage of Figaro; Praeludium; WPA spot on unemployment; Hopak from Mussorgsky's opera The Fair at Sorochyntsi
  - Program No. 14 New York City WPA Negro Melody Singers, 1942; wpa_phono_338; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    You hear the lambs a cryin', men's, women's, mixed choruses; Ezekiel saw the wheel, soloists, men's, women's, mixed choruses; WPA "Morale" spot; Every time I feel the spirit, soloists, men's, women's choruses; The gospel train, soloist, men's, women's choruses; Good news, chariot's coming, soloists, men's, women's choruses.
  - Program No. 15 New York City WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_339; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    March from Nutcracker suite; Baba Yaga, Opus 56; WPA spot - National Defense Emergency; Prelude to ballet Raymonda
  - Program No. 16 United States Navy Band, 1942; wpa_phono_340; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Rustle of spring; Old comrades march; Talk by Rear Admiral Russell R. Waesche, Commandant of the US Coast Guard, on the WPA Coast Guard Academy; Cocoanut dance
  - Program No. 17 The New York City WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_341; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Prelude to Act 3 of Lohengrin; Dance from Golden age; WPA spot on defense jobs and training during wartime; Danse Arabe from Nutcracker Suite
  - Program No. 18 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_342; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to Abduction from the Seraglio; Talk by Fred R. Rauch, Assistant Commissioner WPA, on division of training for defense production; Scherzo, 2nd Movement from Suite for Orchestra; Star-Spangled Banner.
  - Program No. 18A Northern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_343; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Overture to Mignon; Talk by Paul Manship, sculptor, on the value of Art Week, 11/17 - 11/23, to American culture and to the artists of America; Nocturne from ballet music to Coppelia
  - Program No. 19 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_344; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Liebesträume, S. 541; The Bee; Talk by Colonel B. G. Weir, Commanding Officer, March Field, on WPA work at March Field, Riverside CA, Army Air Corps; The Hungarian March from Damnation of Faust.
  - Program No. 19A Northern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_345; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Symphony No. 11 in G minor; Talk by Helen Gahagan, actress [wife of Melvyn Douglas], on the work of the WPA; Prelude to Act 3 of Lohengrin
  - Program No. 20 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_346; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Allegro from Symphony No. 5; WPA spot on school lunch program; Prelude in C Sharp Minor.
  - Program No. 21 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_347; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Blues Movement from Partita Americana; Talk by Major General William P. Upshur, United States Marine Corps, Marine Base San Diego, on WPA work at his base; Waltz Movement from Partita Americana. George Scharl, piano.
  - Program No. 22 Special Christmas Program: Southern California WPA Symphony and Chorus, 1942; wpa_phono_348; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Silent Night, chorus, soloist Alberta Franklin, orchestra; Three Blind Mice from Children's Suite; Pop Goes the Weasel from Children's Suite; Christmas Message delivered by Jean Hersholt, actor, and WPA health programs spot; Polka from Golden Age ballet
  - Program No. 23 Southern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_349; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    The Rat Catcher's Song; Talk by John E. Parrish, Chief, San Diego Fire Department, on the WPA and national defense; 1st Movement from Concerto Grosso. David Hamilton, baritone.
  - Special American Guide Week Program: Northern California WPA Symphony Orchestra, 1942; wpa_phono_350; Grooved analog disc; running time 15:00
    Elegy from Serenade for Strings; Guide Book Spot - WPA writers program American Guide Week; Waltz from Serenade for Strings
  - The Illinois WPA Serves The Nation’s Defense, 1942; wpa_phono_351; Lacquer disc; running time 15:00
    Music performed by Jubilee Singers, directed by Dr. James A. Mundy. O Lord, Jubilee; WPA spot by Chas. [Charles] P. Casey, WPA Administrator, on the WPA in states' defense; Little Wheel a Turnin'; WPA spot by Evelyn S. Byron, Community Service, on the WPA in states' defense; O Rise and Shine.